# **Kishor Chhajed**

kishor.chhajed@gmail.com | 502-337-5788 | San Jose, CA

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kishor-chhajed | GitHub: https://github.com/kchhajed1

Software Engineer seeking full-time position in the Data Domain for professional as well as organizational growth. Strong emphasis on working collaboratively with a like -minded team to ensure optimal results

Professional Profile		
Professional P  Brief Profile	<ul> <li>IT experience in Timekeeping and Insurance domain</li> <li>Experience in creating functional and technical Design Documents.</li> <li>Experienced in Mainframe and Coolgen Technologies.</li> <li>Data Analyst with newly acquired skills</li> <li>A mentor who has trained and motivated the team to implement new approach and solution to many complex situations, also continuously helped the team to be involved in thought process as to how the project can be taken to the next level ahead.</li> <li>Good communication skills, interpersonal skills, self-motivated, quick learner,</li> </ul>	
	smart worker and team player	

### **Education:**

Bachelor of Engineering (Electronics and Telecommunication) for Pune University, India - 2008

## **Technical Skills:**

Programming Languages	Excel, VBA, Python
Data Manipulation and Visualization	Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, Tableau, D3.js
WebTechnologies	HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
Databases	MySQL, Mongo DB, IBM DB2
Mainframe Specific Skills	Cobol, JCL, Easytrieve, CA GEN (Coolgen)
Other	Git, Flask, command line

# **Projects and Applications:**

Real Investment in South Carolina – https://github.com/kchhajed1/real\_estate\_analysis\_sc

The Tech industry is exciting, but unpredictable. A back-up income strategy is needed for happy and early retirement. The project is to identify places in South Carolina for investment which will yield good return of investment few years down the line

• Determine the real estate investment criteria in South Carolina depending on the Job Growth, School Rating, Crime Rate and Property Value to Rent for zip codes in South Carolina

- Gather data from Zillow, Great Schools, Crime Rate and Bureau for Labor Statistics to assemble a dataset on over 400 zip codes
- Summary statistics and visualizations created using Python, Pandas, APIs, Contour Maps, Folium and Matplotlib

#### **Experience:**

### Cognizant Technology Solutions - 09/2016 - Present

<u>Client:</u> <u>Kaiser Permanente</u> <u>Role:</u> <u>Sr. Software Developer</u>

<u>Project</u>: <u>Timekeeping application</u> - Kaiser Permanente has an in-house legacy Timekeeping application which allows doctors, nurses, pharmacist etc. to clock in and out for hourly employees. Capturing of these hours is essential to calculate the employee pay correctly.

Skillset: Cobol, CA Gen, Client-Server Encyclopedia, DB2, VSAM, CICS, MQ, Series, Sorts, JCL

CoolSoft LLC - 05/2014 - 09/2016

<u>Client:</u> <u>PacifiCorp (Portland, OR)</u> Role: Sr. Software Developer

<u>Project:Solar Subscription</u> - This was a pilot project where in PacifiCorp allowed the users to enroll into Solar Subscription in the state of UTAH. This way the users need not maintain the solar panels on their roof instead PacifiCorp would be generating the solar energy which would be supplied to the customers. The IT infrastructure needs to be modified to development/enhancement of new/existing programs that would take care of the enrollment, maintenance and billing for the newly enrolled customer

<u>Client:</u> <u>State of Nebraska (Lincoln, NE)</u>

Role: Sr. Software Developer

<u>Project</u>: <u>N-FOCUS</u> - is a front-end application used by the field officers for day to day business. A large portion of the backend functionality is performed using the batch mainframe programs to send out letters, reports etc. to the end users

Skillset: COBOL, CA Gen, Client-Server Encyclopedia, DB2, VSAM, CICS, MQ Series, Sorts, JCL

Syntel Ltd - 10/2009 - 05/2014

<u>Client:</u> <u>Humana Inc (Louisville, KY)</u> <u>Role:</u> <u>Sr. Software Developer</u>

<u>Project</u>: <u>Premium Billing System</u> - is the core sub system of Humana which deals with billing of monthly Premium, invoicing generation, cash postings, collections, sub-ledger maintenance and account

reconciliation. PBS takes care of billing of all the customers across all the platforms

Skillset: COBOL, CA Gen, Client-Server Encyclopedia, DB2, JCL